JULIAN ALZATE – BACKEND DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

Work in areas related to databases and programming, which give me the possibility to apply my skills acquired during my degree; with the ability to work with languages such as PHP, HTML, CSS, Tailwindcss, JavaScript, XML, JQuery and MYSQ, MongoDB, SQL Server and PostgreSQL databases; using frameworks such as DHTMLX, Bootstrap, Laravel, Nodejs, Nestjs, Vuejs, Express.js, with the ability to make UML diagrams. Experience working with the WordPress CMS. Knowledge of Git and GitHub.

SKILLS

- Programming Tools/ Languages: Php, Javascript, Ajax, CSS, XML, Wordpress, Git, Github, Postman.
- Frameworks: Laravel, Nodejs, Express.js, Nestjs, Vuejs, Bootstrap, Tailwindcss
- Databases: MYSQL, PostgreSQL, SqLite. MongoDB, Sql Server

WORK EXPERIENCE

<u>Aug, 2023 - Present</u> Backend Developer - Ingenes México.

Project: Ingenes Softwares. Team size: 20 members.

Tasks performed:

- Code applications to meet acceptance criteria defined by clients.
- Generate application documentation for implementation to production.
- Provide support for Ingenes applications.

Tools: Api (REST) \cdot Sql Server \cdot Postman \cdot PHP \cdot SQL \cdot MongoDB \cdot JavaScript \cdot Bootstrap \cdot Node.js \cdot NestJS \cdot VueJs

Nov, 2021 - Jun, 2023 Backend Developer - Soaint Panamá.

Project: Transforming Lives.
Team size: 10 members.

Tasks performed:

• Development of a PDF417 Api for identity card scanner and data processing using Nodejs and Express.js.

- Create an API with Nodejs to upload an image with a created endpoint.
- Create modules in a donation system using Laravel in backend and PostgreSQL to manage the databases.
- Development of a dashboard with an interactive clock to monitor projects by province, district and corregimiento, with statistics according to the progress of each project using Laravel in the backend, Bootstrap for the frontend and MySQL database.
- Database debugging for a medication application in MySQL and functionality test in the application.
- Creation of Api to search for drug images using Google api using the Tesseract library with Laravel and Python.

Tools: Api (REST) · Laravel · PostgreSQL · Postman · PHP · SQL · JavaScript · Bootstrap · Node.js

Mar, 2021 - Aug 2021 Webmaster - Shammah

Project: Shammah clients. Team size: 15 Members.

Tasks performed:

- Update Shammah clients webpages using Divi, Elementor and Woocommerce.
- Implement a new Theme for Shammah webpage.

Tools: Elementor \cdot WooCommerce \cdot CSS \cdot PHP \cdot JavaScript \cdot WordPress

Nov, 2020 - Mar, 2021 Telematic Engineer - National University of Colombia

Project: Organizational Relationship Strengthening

Team size: 15 members.

Tasks performed:

 Development and monitoring of technical aspects to improve the functioning of the University's digital tools using Php, JavaScript, Bootstrap and MySQL database.

Tools: PHP · SQL · JavaScript · MySQL · Bootstrap · FTP

Aug, 2020 - Nov, 2020 Media Developer- Catholic University of Manizales

Project: Interactive Games for Educational Program.

Team size: 5 members.

Tasks performed:

 Development using Bootstrap, CSS and Javascript for interactive programs in Moodle and Wordpress. Tools: Moodle · CSS · SQL · JavaScript · Wordpress

<u>Jul, 2020 - Aug, 2020</u> Web Developer - Pulzo

Project: Pulzo Client.

Team size: 10 members.

Tasks performed:

• Development, technical improvement and optimization of a web page developed in WordPress using PHP, Bootstrap and JavaScript, and database management with Mysql.

Tools: CSS · PHP · MYSQL · JavaScript · WordPress

Nov, 2016 - Present Freelancer Developer

Project: Personal Projects - Software and Webpages for clients.

Team size: up to 3 members.

Tasks performed:

- Marketing support application for management of work teams for systems multilevel: Prospect and referral management system, as well as landing pages of obtaining prospects to manage the relationship with each one of them (contacts, leads, campaigns, activity efficiency, scheduling and event reminders using platform, email and SMS) Using Php, Dhtmlx and MySQL database.
- Web directory for Colombian links, segmented by categories to generate traffic to your colombialink.net websites using Bootstrap, JavaScript, Php and MySQL.
- Development of an application for customer management and payment reminder. Cedeno & Mendez using Php, Dhtmlx, JavaScript, Bootstrap and MySQL database.
- Web page development for the Plei 2034 project of the National University of Manizales using Css, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Php and MySQL database.

Tools: Api (REST) · Dhtmlx · JQuery · PostgreSQL · Postman · PHP · MYSQL · JavaScript · Bootstrap · Node.js · Wordpress

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Telematic Engineering, Catholic University of Manizales

• Speciality: Php, Javascript, JQuery, Ajax.

English B1, Autónoma University of Manizales.

CERTIFICATIONS

Fullstack Developer Javascript - Platzi.

- PHP Backend Platzi.
- Inbound Certified Hubspot.
- Cloud Computing Course Google Certification.
- General Databases and Management Systems SENA.
- Scrum Fundamentals Certified SCRUMstudy.
- JavaScript Tutorial SoloLearn.